Thomas J. Delaney,
Ballyboggan Lower,
Castlebridge,
Co. Wexford,
Ireland, Y35 A4A3
thomas.delaney@posteo.net
(+353) 086 127 5282

December 22, 2020

Marshall Wace LLP, George House, 131 Sloane Street, London, SW1X 9AT, United Kingdom

## Dear Ms. Thorne,

I am writing to you to apply for a suitable position in Marshall Wace LLP, most likely in quantitative research, quantitative trading or something related.

I worked in the Marshall Wace London and Hong Kong offices before in 2013/2014, as a kdb+ engineer. I enjoyed the working atmosphere, and I was interested in the work done by the QR and QT teams but I was not qualified enough for that work at that time.

In the meantime, I have done an MSc in Informatics and I have worked as a data engineer in Edinburgh airport. I have completed a PhD in Computer Science. I have presented my research at number of international conferences. I have done an internship in CheckRisk, a risk analysis company. I have also worked as a teaching assistant and an exam supervisor. Lastly, I have developed and matured personally.

During the MSc and PhD, I learned and implemented the skills that I was lacking in 2014. So I am a good candidate for Marshall Wace now. Thank you for your consideration. I'll look forward to your response.

Sincerely,

Thomas J. Delaney

# Thomas J. Delaney, PhD

(+353) 0861275282  $\diamond$  thomas.delaney@posteo.net

Ballyboggan Lower  $\diamond$  Castlebridge

Co. Wexford  $\diamond$  Ireland  $\diamond$  Y35 A4A3

**①**: thomasjdelaney  $\diamond$  **in**: tjwdelaney

#### **EDUCATION**

## University of Bristol

Sept 2016 - July 2020

PhD in Computer Science. Specialised in computational neuroscience.

Thesis: 'Investigating, implementing, and creating methods for analysing large neuronal ensembles'

Multiple international conference presentations

Publication in preparation: 'Local and global neural ensembles at fast and slow timescales'

# University of Edinburgh

Sept 2014 - Sept 2015

MSc in Informatics

Thesis: 'How informative are retinal ganglion cell responses about visual stimuli?'

Modules included: Neural Computation, Machine Learning & Pattern Recognition, Reinforcement Learning, Neural Information Processing, etc.

Overall Result: Distinction

# Trinity College, Dublin

Sept 2007 - June 2011

B.A. in Mathematics

Including two years of Theoretical Physics

Final Year Project on Quantum Topos Theory, Poster Project 'Biomechanics of Human Motion'

Modules included: Mathematical Neuroscience, Information Theory, Functional Analysis, etc.

Overall Result: 1.1

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Neuromatch Academy

July 2020

Teaching Assistant

Online (Bristol, England)

- · Teaching assistant for 3 week Computational Neuroscience Summer school. Entirely online.
- · Responsible for the learning outcomes of a group of seven BSc and MSc students in attendance.
- · Facilitated completion of daily workshops, and oversaw work on two group projects.

# University of Bristol

Sept 2016 - July 2020

Teaching Assistant

Bristol, England

- · Teaching Assistant for Computer Science and Engineering Mathematics undergraduate and MSc courses:
  - $\circ$  Applied Statistics, 3rd year & MSc course, 2018 2020,  $\sim 80$  students.
  - $\circ$  Machine Learning, 3rd year & MSc course, 2019,  $\sim$  300 students.
  - $\circ$  Data Structures & Algorithms, 2nd year course, 2019,  $\sim$  200 students.
  - $\circ$  Algorithms, 1st year course, 2018,  $\sim$  200 students.
- · Marking for undergraduate courses:
  - $\circ$  Algorithms, 1st year course, 2018,  $\sim$  200 students.
  - $\circ$  Computational Neuroscience, 3rd year & MSc course, 2018 2019,  $\sim 300$  students.
- · Prepared workshop for prospective computer science students on university open day.

#### University of Bristol

Chief Examination Invigilator

January 2017 - July 2020 Bristol, England

- · Supervised  $\sim 50$  exam rooms.
- · Included exam rooms for a single student or up to 800 students.
- · Responsible for set-up, role taking, reportage of malpractice, safe transport of exam scripts and papers.

CheckRisk LLP.

June 2018 - September 2018

Research Intern

Bath, England

- · Internship at financial risk assessment company.
- · Researched cutting-edge forecasting methods including statistical, machine learning and hybrid methods, including recurrent neural networks.
- · Applied these methods to financial data to evaluate domain suitability.

# Edinburgh Airport Ltd.

Jan 2016 - Aug 2016

Data Engineer

Edinburgh, Scotland

- · Worked as a key member of the Airport's Digital team with a mandate to change every interaction with the airport using technology, data and innovation.
- · Main responsibility was taking data from airport businesses and extracting insights efficiently.
- · Worked with teams such as Commercial, Security, Airfield, Forecasting and Planning to extract, transform and load data, making these datasets useful for these teams, and Edinburgh Airport's senior management.

#### First Derivatives Plc.

June 2011 - Aug 2014

Consultant Software Engineer

Newry, Ireland

- · Worked as a software engineer on in-house projects, and as a consultant for financial companies.
- · Four months as kdb+ consultant in Morgan Stanley New York offices, working on the creation and upkeep of a large historical and real-time financial database.
- · Four months as kdb+ consultant and team leader in off-shore development centre for Morgan Stanley.
- · Seventeen months as kdb+ consultant in a highly responsible role in the London based hedge fund Marshall Wace Asset Management. Worked in the London and Hong Kong offices.
- · Final three months in team-leader role utilising in-house software for performance reporting on First Derivatives FX trading platform.

#### TECHNICAL STRENGTHS & ONLINE PROFILES

Computer Languages Python, Julia, Matlab, Bash, q/kdb+, Java, c++, Batch, LATEX

Spoken Languages English, Irish (proficient), French (basic)

Protocols & APIs FIX messaging protocol, Geneos monitoring API

Databases kdb+, MySQL

Tools git, SVN, Vim, crontab, Autosys, Eclipse, Scoop for Parallel Processing

#### TRAINING COURSES

## **Advanced Computing Research Centre**

Sept 2018 - Present

Training courses available to University of Bristol students  $\mathcal{E}$  staff

Bristol, England

· Modern C++

- · High performance computing
- · Introduction to modern Fortran
- $\cdot$  Version control using Git
- · Applied data analysis with Python